<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<r id="udmfin" xml:lang="udm">
   <lics xml:space="preserve">
      <lic xml:lang="en">
This code is made available under a Creative Commons Attribution license
<a>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/no/deed.en</a>.
You are free to copy, distribute and adapt the work, as long as you always give
proper attribution using the attribution text below.
For the full license text, see the link above.</lic>
      <ref>The material is based on the following dictionaries compiled at the University of Turku, Finland:
Sergej Maksimov, Vadim Danilov &amp; Sirkka Saarinen: Udmurttilais-suomalainen sanakirja (2008)
Proofreading of the electronic material: Tomi Koivunen.

Funding of the online dictionary: The Kone Foundation (Finland).

         Source code available at <a>https://victorio.uit.no/langtech/trunk/</a>.</ref>
      <sourcenote>
The material was prepared for electronic publication by Jack Rueter.
     THIS TEXT HAS BEEN TAKEN FROM THE ORIGINAL PDF DOCUMENT, which may have caused sporadic problems in its transformation into electronic form. 

This is NOT a fully styled and published dictionary.
Possible errors following proofreading are, e. g., substitution of special fonts with wrong signs, combining of rows between columns, and the loss of the original signs for syllable stress.
     <a>mailto:giellatekno@hum.uit.no</a>.
     Please also note that the entries are not necessarily sorted,
     or could be wrongly sorted.
      </sourcenote>
   </lics>

<e>
   <lg>
     <l pos="CC">только</l><stress>тоʼлько</stress>
   </lg>
   <mg ind="1th">
     <tg xml:lang="fin">
       <t>mutta</t>
     </tg>
     <xg><x>мон кошко, только берло эн йыркуръяськы</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">minä lähden, mutta älä sitten suutu</xt>
     </xg>
   </mg>
   </e>
<e>
   <lg>
     <l pos="CC">а</l>
     <stg>
       <st Contlex="CC_">а</st>
     </stg>
   </lg>
   <mg ind="1th"><posType>advers.</posType>
     <tg xml:lang="fin">
       <t Pos="CC">mutta</t>
       <tCtn> <re xml:lang="udm">ӧвӧлтон бере</re>
       <t Pos="CC">vaan</t>
       </tCtn>
     </tg>
     <xg><x>мон та книгаез лыдӟи ни, а тон ӧд на</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">minä olen jo lukenut tämän kirjan, mutta sinä et ole vielä;</xt>
     </xg>
     <xg><x>тынад ӧвӧл со малпанэд, а мынам</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">se ei ole sinun ajatuksesi, vaan minun</xt>
     </xg>
   </mg>
   <mg ind="2th"> <posType>advers.</posType>
     <tg xml:lang="fin">
       <t Pos="CC">mutta</t>
       <t Pos="CC">niin kuitenkin</t>
       <t Pos="CC">kuitenkin</t>
     </tg>
     <xg><x>мон кемалась сое вунэтӥ ни, а тон яʼлаʼн тодад ваиськод</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">minä olen jo unohtanut sen kauan sitten, mutta sinä muistelet yhä vielä(kin)</xt>
     </xg>
   </mg>
   <mg ind="3th"> <posType>kopl.</posType>
     <tg xml:lang="fin">
       <t Pos="CC">ja</t>
       <tCtn><re xml:lang="udm">ӧвӧлтон дыръя</re>
       <t Pos="CC">eikä</t>
       </tCtn>
     </tg>
     <xg><x>гурт дортӥ шур бызе, а со сьӧрын нюлэс сылэ</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">kylän vieressä virtaa joki, ja sen takana on metsä;</xt>
     </xg>
     <xg><x>уксёез солэн ӧвӧл, а ужамез уг поты</x>
       <xt xml:lang="fin">hänellä ei ole rahaa, eikä hän halua työskennellä</xt>
     </xg>
     <variants>
       <l_syn type="vrt0">нош<rom ind="1"/></l_syn>
     </variants>
   </mg>
</e>
</r>
